[{"question":"<p><strong>____________ is an end product of digestion of fat.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Glucose","Fatty acid","Amino acid","Fructose"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Asexual reproduction in Hydra sp. is commonly by ____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Binary fission","Fragmentation","Budding","Separation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Benedict&rsquo;s solution is used to test for ___&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carbohydrate","Lipid","Protein","Vitamins"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pepsin is an enzyme that digests ___&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Starch","Sugar","Lipid","Protein"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The enzyme that curdles milk is_____________&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pepsin","Ptyalin","Renin","Amylase"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the enzyme that begins digestion of starch in the mouth?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ptyalin","Maltase","Amylase","Sucrase"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Autotrophs are also described as _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Consumers","Decomposers","Carnivores","Producers"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following factors does not control population growth?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Food shortage","Emigration","Predation","Abundance of food"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>During digestion of food, passage of chyme through the duodenum enables it to become a watery liquid called__________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Digested food","Chymatic product","Chyle","Soluble"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the respiratory system of man, diffusion of gases takes place in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Trachea","Bronchi","Alveoli","Bronchioles"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a function of the skin&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Excretion","Protection","Homeostasis","Reproduction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The basis for growth and asexual reproduction is&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Meiosis","Cytokinesis","Mitosis","Cytogenesis"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The process which ensures that the chromosome number for each species of organism remain constant from generation to generation is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fission","Fusion","Meiosis","Mitosis"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a major factor in variation among organisms?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inbreeding","Backcrossing","Test crossing","Sexual reproduction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>____________ is an example of an invertebrate&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Millipede","Fish","Toad","Snake"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mutation theory of organic evolution was propounded by&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gregor Mendel","Hugo de Vries","Jean Lamarck","Charles Darwin"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The theory of natural selection was developed by&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lamarck and Darwin","Darwin and Wallace","Wallace and Mendel","Mendel and Lamarck"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sources is not an evidence of evolution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fossil records","Comparative anatomy","Comparative embryology","Human behavior"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______________ is an endoparasite&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Earthworm","Tapeworm","Mosquito","Housefly"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following are major groups of the plant kingdom EXCEPT&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bryophyta","Chlorophyta","Pteridophyta","Spermatophyta"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_____________is a form of sexual reproduction&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Grafting","Budding","Fission","Conjugation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sexual reproduction in Spirogyra is called&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fertilization","Symbiosis","Conjugation","Reproduction"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The carrier of the hereditary characters in plants is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cell","Nucleus","Chromosome","Gene"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>All are necessary for photosynthesis except_____________&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Water","Chlorophyll","Sunlight","Oxygen"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which is the correct order in an evolutionary sequence for the following plant groups?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bacteria-->ferns--> algae--> mosses--> seed plants.","Bacteria --> ferns--> mosses--> algae -->seed plants.","Bacteria -->algae-->mosses-->ferns-->seed plants.","Bacteria-->mosses--> algae--> ferns--> seed plants."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What type of fruit is a mango fruit?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Berry","Hesperidium","Drupe","Nut"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following species exhibit an aerial root?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ficus","Centrosema","Antigonon","Lantana"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of Vascular tissues is __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Trichome","Xylem","Stomata","Epidermis"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The living part of phloem tissue is&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sieve plate","Companion cell","Sieve element","Cytoplasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following tissues are made up of dead cells&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Meristems","Xylem vessels","Cambium","Mesophyll"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A plant vacuole contains<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dissolved chemicals, sugars, salts, pigments and crystals","Waste products of metabolism, DNA, RNA and crystals","Pigments, crystals, DNA and waste products of metabolism","RNA, DNA, sugars and salts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Starch granules in plants is equivalent to _____________ granules in animals&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Food","Chromatin","Lysosome","Glycogen"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a plant excretory product?&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oil","Cytokinin","Resin","Amino acids"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"}]